Look, we all know
Scully has the hardest head,
but what concerns me
is the speed factor.
- Squad, listen up!
- Not now, Terry.
We're having an argument
about who would win in a fight
if we couldn't use our arms.
Everyone agrees, I'd bite the best.
Meaningless! True strength comes
from the pelvis, not the mouth.
- There's been an assassination attempt!
- What?
And you let us just sit around
talking about Boyle's pelvis?
I didn't let you!
Councilman Bosworth was giving
a speech at Garfield Plaza.
He was shot in the shoulder.
Now, he's in stable condition,
but the shooter's still at large!
We have to move!
We're locking down a ten-block
radius around the scene.
No traffic in or out.
We think our man
is still inside the area.
ESU is on-site.
I'll be leading the op
from a mobile command center.
Santiago is running perimeter control.
Peralta, you're in charge
of the manhunt for the shooter.
Oh, my God, it's a manhunt.
And I'm the Manhunter.
And I'm your sidekick, the Boyhunter.
- Come on, dude.
- I'm gonna be on the news.
I'm gonna look straight
into the camera and say,
"If the shooter is watching,
I hope you like living
between St. Charles Place
and Connecticut Ave."
[siren wails]
- I don't get it.
- It's from "Monopoly."
That's where jail is.
Whatever, it was a good line.
Keep briefing!
- _
- Diaz, Santiago,
the Command Tent's
on the northeast corner.
We need to work fast.
The mayor's only given us five hours
until the barricades are lifted.
Five hours?
Tell him the Manhunter only needs one.
Love that,
but I'm gonna keep it at five.
It's already way too little time.
All right, I'm seeing security cameras.
I need all that footage.
I need forensics
to run a full sweep of...
Hey, what are all these
civilians doing here?
Who's responsible for securing
the area, who screwed this up?
Hi, I'm Officer Debbie Fogle.
I'm so sorry,
my partner's on crowd control.
I don't know where he went.
It's his first week on the job,
so he's still learning the ropes.
All right, listen, Fogle.
We have a councilman in the hospital
and his shooter is still at large.
We don't have time
for this incompetence.
I want your partner
off the case, what's his name?
It's Raymond Holt.
Oh!
It's Dad... I mean, Captain Holt!
I mean, Captain Dad.
I mean, Officer Holt.
I mean, Officer Dad.
Yep, that was it.
Officer Dad, I found it.
[upbeat music]
♪
Sync & corrections by emeline-whovian
www.addic7ed.com
Detective, I thought
I saw a clue on the sidewalk.
I apologize for not
properly securing the scene.
No need to apologize,
I wasn't even that mad.
You said you wanted
whoever messed up off the case.
It doesn't matter.
The point is, no one
needs to get in trouble.
Look, you don't have to pity me
just because Madeline Wuntch
demoted me for a year.
I've been stripped of my accomplishments
and lost the respect
of everyone in my life...
including my dog.
Cheddar? No.
Yes! Now...
- he only poops for Kevin.
- Oh, sir.
We don't have time to take all this in,
there's a shooter on the loose!
Are you guys gonna be okay
working together or not?
Of course we will,
I took an oath to protect this city
no matter what my rank.
I have no problem
with Detective Peralta
being my commander.
And I have no problem commanding him.
Here, watch this.
Captain, will you please
lock down North 3rd Street,
if that's okay with you, Captain?
It certainly is!
Impressed?
You said "please" and you
called him "Captain" twice.
Yeah, we don't have time
for this, Lieutenant.
There's a shooter on the loose!
- _
- Traffic is shut down.
Civilians are being funneled
into the checkpoints.
Good, just wish my guys over here
could be a little more efficient.
Yeah, I'm looking at you,
Detective Fuzzy Paws!
Is this Amy-hates-dogs-Amy
or Amy-extra-stressed-Amy?
It's both Amys!
I'm under a lot of pressure.
And also, that dog is a piece of trash!
- [groans]
- Okay.
I can tell something else is going on,
you don't have to pretend
to be mad at the dog.
First of all, I'm not pretending.
That dog sucks!
Also... [sighs]
My period's late,
I think I might be pregnant.
- Oh, damn.
- I can't be pregnant!
Jake and I agreed to wait
at least a year until we tried.
I haven't found an OB,
I'm not on any preschool waiting lists,
and I spent all of yesterday
in a room with Hitchcock
and his new cologne,
which can't be good for the baby...
it is literally called
Zika!
Okay, relax,
You're probably not pregnant,
it's entirely possible
Hitchcock's cologne
disrupted your cycle.
Right, yes.
That is a very real possibility.
- Santiago!
- Ah!
What's going on here?
Is everything okay?
Yeah, totes!
Right, Rosa?
Uh, totes.
Why is everyone being all weird today?
Just get back to work and be normal.
Yes, sir! Will do, we'll be normal.
Nothing to stress about here.
Hey, Fuzzy Paws!
I'm paying you to work,
not lick your butthole!
Yeah, I'm gonna get you
a pregnancy test.
- _
- [funky music]
Okay, I know you haven't
done this in a while,
so here's a tip... keep your hat on.
Because of all the standing still,
the pigeons think we're statues
and they will poop on you or peck you.
Both are bad.
Thank you for the helpful tip.
Oh, I've got a ton of them.
They're mostly about
the dangers of standing.
A year on the beat
without prescription insoles
can take two years off your life.
Any way to speed the process up?
[laughs]
Okay, I've got
a funny guy for a partner.
But seriously, you have to
monitor your foot health.
I'll gonna send you
a pedometer app that I use.
You're gonna love it.
It has robust social features.
We can give each other "foot-fives"!
No, thank you,
I keep count of my steps in my head,
like a normal person.
I'm up to 6,743 for the day.
- _
- Okay Boyle, it's time for the Manhunter
to hunt... man.
♪ Ooh, here he comes ♪
♪ Watch out, men, he'll hunt you down ♪
♪ Jake's a Manhunter! ♪
Charles... I love that.
Keep doing the song
while I work the scene.
You got it!
[sings melody
to Hall & Oates' "Maneater"]
Okay, bullet lodged there
is 4 feet below the hole in the backdrop
indicating a trajectory
of about 15 degrees,
which means the shot was taken
from either the second or third floor
of one of the buildings
across the plaza.
♪ Ooh, here he comes ♪
That building's windows don't open.
♪ Watch out men, he'll hunt you down ♪
- That one's obscured by trees.
- ♪ Ooh, here he comes
Which means that the shooter
must've been located...
On the sky bridge.
♪ Jake's a Manhunter ♪
- Officer Holt.
- Mm.
I thought I stationed you...
not here!
Right.
I'm just here in the plaza
looking for, um...
this!
A half-eaten box of McNuggets?
- Yup, it's my lunch.
- Uh-huh.
And what type of food is a McNugget?
Some type of a... paella?
You had to know that was a bad guess.
Well, the point is, I needed my paella
and I noticed the sky bridge,
so I thought I might be of some help,
but I'll just go back
and stand next to a piece of police tape
and do nothing.
Wait, stop.
How would you like to stick around
and assist on the case?
You sure, Jake, I mean,
there's only room for one Manhunter.
Boyle is right,
I don't want to overstep.
You're not overstepping.
I mean, he interrupted
the song, but whatever.
Great, I'll just leave my paella
on the ground, save it for later.
We all know that's not your lunch!
So, the shooter was standing right here.
A standard long gun
would've ejected the casing
right over...
there, where Holt
is already putting down
an evidence marker.
Yes, I found it quite quickly.
Great, thank you for saving
me the trouble of doing my job.
Oh, sorry.
Would you like me to pick
the evidence marker back up
so you can place it on the ground?
- Yes!
- No, of course not.
Good work.
BOTH: I bet the shooter went that way.
- Sorry.
- Yeah, it's okay.
BOTH: Follow me to the service entrance.
Ugh, we did it again. I'm so sorry.
- It's really no problem.
- Great!
Follow me, everyone!
Wait, what?
Security footage showed
no cars leaving the area,
so our shooter
must've left here on foot.
He's taking over your case, Jake.
You have to stop him.
Well, you know, it takes a true leader
to let someone else lead.
Ugh, sounds exactly
like something I would say.
Snap out of it.
Look, it's fine, I just...
I feel sorry for him, okay?
His assignment was
standing next to tape.
I'm still gonna crack the case.
- I cracked the case.
- Come on!
Hot dog man, tell them what you told me.
I saw a guy, mid-height, brown hair,
and a green hoodie with an owl on it.
He had a big bag
and he was running like hell.
It sounds like our guy.
All right, let's call it in to
give a statement to the press.
Great idea.
He knows that I meant I would
give the statement, right?
And if the shooter's watching,
I hope you like living
between St. Charles Place
and Connecticut Avenue.
Because that's where jail is
in "Monopoly."
A great line from a great man,
or should I say,
Manhunter.
Yeah, he overstepped.
- _
- Boyle, gather everyone up.
Oh, we starting a burn book about Holt?
Let's drag him, baby!
No, someone saw our hoodie guy.
Right, we'll do the burn book later.
Attention, everyone,
we have a possible sighting
of our shooter on Hoyt Street.
Detective Boyle and I
will take Alpha unit.
- Smith, Fox...
- You guard the burn book.
- Charles, no.
- Stand down.
You take Bravo unit.
The rest of you,
continue to sweep the area
in case this lead doesn't pan out.
The clock is ticking, go, go, go!
Where should I go, Detective?
I'd love to be of service.
Captain Holt! I mean... dude!
I haven't seen you since
your big news conference
which I just loved.
Ray, there you are!
I can't believe
you left your post again.
Detectives, I'm sorry for
my partner's bad boy behavior.
I am not a bad boy,
I'm trying to catch bad boys!
If anything, I'm a good boy.
That's exactly what a bad boy would say.
It's definitely not,
and no need to apologize,
we have a job to do.
Great! Where do you want us?
Someone matching our shooter's profile
was just seen over on Atlantic and 4th,
I need you both there
immediately, can you handle it?
Absolutely not,
it sounds like
way too much responsibility.
Don't listen to Debbie. We're on it!
All right. Bye!
What's going on?
The guy's on Hoyt Street.
I know, I gave Holt
a fake lead to get rid of him.
Don't worry, I'm still...
the Manhunter.
♪ He's the Manhunter!
♪ And the boy who he hunts with ♪
- What's that song?
- The Boyhunter song!
♪ Boyhunter
♪ Down by the schoolyard
Why is he by the schoolyard?
- He's gotta protect the kids!
- Sounds terrible.
- Really, I don't hear it!
- Let's just go.
- _
- Okay, good news.
I found a bodega in the containment zone
and got a bunch of pregnancy tests.
- A bunch?
- Yeah.
It's a New York bodega,
you can't be too cautious.
Good point. Yep, expired ten years ago.
Open. And used!
Made of gummies? Why?
Weirdly vibrating.
This is for teens. That's dark.
This is good.
Great, let's do this.
Hey, Santiago,
nice work at checkpoint one.
Wait, why are you guys
being all weird again?
We're not being weird.
Do not dab!
I wasn't going to.
I know what's going on here.
- You do?
- Yep.
You're talking about me.
I know 'cause my daughters
are doing the same thing.
Every time I go in that room,
they get all weird and quiet.
That's 'cause
they're making fun of Daddy.
Is that what you're doing,
making fun of Daddy?
First off...
- Yeah, I heard it, I'm sorry.
- Great.
Secondly, we're not talking about you.
What are you talking about, then?
Our favorite...
porns.
- What?
- It's true.
We have specific favorite porns.
- [whispers] And we're talking about 'em.
- [whispers] Yeah.
Okay, legally, I feel as though
I need to back away.
But I want it to be known that
I still do not believe you.
Get back to work!
Eh, that went well. All right.
Let's take this thing
and get it over with.
- I can't.
- What? Why?
I have no pee inside of me.
I'm pee-free, Rosa!
What do I do, what do I do?
Drink water.
Oh, yeah. You're smart.
You're a very good friend,
I'm glad you're here.
♪
Street's clear.
No sign of the shooter, where'd he go?
- Shh, shh, shh, shh, shh.
- Why are you shushing me?
I'm doing that thing where I listen
really closely for a noise clue,
like glass breaking or trash rustling.
Cool! Is it working?
No, not yet.
- Because I'm talking?
- Well, it's not helping.
Right, right, right. I'll be quiet.
You don't have to say
you'll be quiet, just be quiet.
Okay. I'm sorry for not being quiet.
Once again, don't have to say.
Just wanna be clear what I'm doing.
- Understood. I'm just gonna listen.
- Okay.
I'll be very quiet.
Don't have to say it.
Just wanna make sure
you know what I'm doing.
- Please stop.
- So I don't throw you.
Okay, stop talking.
- I'll stop talking.
- Great.
I'll make sure I don't do that again.
All right, Charles,
I love you, but you ruined it.
[dumpster clatters]
BOTH: Trash rustle!
He's running, call it in!
[funky music]
♪
[steam hisses]
I'll follow, you cut him off!
♪
[tires screech]
Damn it!
[grunts]
Nice, Charles!
Name's not Charles, it's...
Boyhunter.
You know what, you earned it.
Way to get your boy, Boyhunter!
All right, let's get our perp
back to the Nine-Nine.
I'll tell Jeffords to lift the lockdown.
Detective Peralta!
I see you got the man
you were looking for.
With your help, officer!
I really couldn't have
done it without you.
No, this was all you.
We were in a completely wrong location.
Which was a huge relief to me.
Plus, we got a lot of steps in.
I'm drowning in foot-fives.
Well, no need to focus on who was where
or what a foot-five is,
we gotta start brainstorming
headlines for tomorrow's paper.
I got one.
"The Only Assassin in this City
is Jake Peralta
Because He Just Killed This Case."
I don't know if we want to make it seem
like I'm the assassin.
Yeah, good thinking.
How about this, "Hero Cop Saves City,
"Pitt, Clooney Circling
To Play Him In Biopic."
- Hunks!
- I have a headline.
"Pitt, Clooney Laugh At Jake Peralta
For Arresting the Wrong Man."
Well, I don't know if they
would laugh at me for saving...
what, did you just say
I got the wrong man?
What do you mean we got the wrong man?
What are you talking about?
You know how you sent Debbie and me off
- on a wild goose chase?
- Oh, so you figured that out?
Well, Debbie did.
She's quite the detective.
Oh, I'm really not.
I'm just always being given
meaningless tasks
and I'm not complaining.
So what, you're just saying
we have the wrong guy now,
because you're upset
about the fake lead?
No, I'm saying you have
the wrong guy because you do.
When I realized your lead
was nothing but hooey,
I went back to re-interview the
hot dog man, but he was gone.
And why was that? Debbie, tell 'em!
Oh, no, I don't want
to be a part of this.
Because the hot dog man is the shooter.
What? That seems like a reach.
Sometimes, when you reach,
you grab the truth.
- Sorry, Jake, he turned it around on me.
- Come on!
The hot dog man gave a false statement
to throw us off the scent
and then vanished
while we were off
looking for the wrong guy.
Face it, you're no Manhunter.
If anything, you're a Wrong Manhunter.
[gasps] How dare you.
You know what? This is crazy.
You're just making up a solve
because you can't stand
the fact that you got demoted.
You've been trying to hijack
this case all day.
I was only trying to help.
If I'm such a headache,
then why didn't you reassign me?
Because I felt sorry for you.
I told you to treat me
like any uniformed officer.
It's not my fault
that you don't know
how to give an order!
Okay, fine. Here's one.
We're lifting the lockdown,
go pick up cones.
- Ooh, I love cone duty!
- Debbie, can it!
We have the wrong guy.
You cannot lift the lockdown.
- Go pick up cones, that's an order.
- No!
- Fine, then you're off the case!
- Good.
Do I still get to pick up cones?
BOTH: No!
Amy, stop. You've had enough water.
I can hear it sloshing around
inside you.
I know, but I still can't pee!
- I'm too stressed.
- You need to calm down.
You know what helps me relax?
- Kicking stuff?
- Absolutely.
So, what or who do you wanna kick?
That guy looks pretty kickable. Hey!
I'm not kicking anybody, okay?
I just need, like, some calming noises.
Okay, close your eyes.
Okay.
Glub, glub, glub.
- What is that?
- It's a babbling brook.
Glub, glub, glub.
You know what? It's pretty good.
Thank you. Everybody, shut up!
Glub, glub, glub, glub, glub, glub.
Why is the tent so quiet?
Is everybody talking about me now?
- Nobody is talking about you.
- Sure.
Terry walks into a tent
and everybody just happens
to stop talking
at the same damn time?
You are gaslighting me
just like my daughters!
Terry, I think you're being paranoid.
I'm not paranoid!
I put a recording device
in my girls' room.
You planted a bug
in your daughters' room?
I do what I have to do.
They said I look like a giant triangle!
- Is that an insult?
- I don't know!
But they were laughing like it was,
and it hurt just the same!
Don't have kids!
Well, that ruined everything.
I know we got kicked off the case,
but there is good news.
I unlocked a new accessory
for my Foot Friend avatar:
a sandal!
Debbie, wait. Change of plans.
We're not going back to the precinct.
Are we gonna go rogue and pick up cones?
Oh, we're going way more
rogue than picking up cones.
Listen, it's unlikely our shooter
had his own hot dog cart...
where'd he get it from?
Please don't make me help you with this.
My guess is the food cart garage
just two blocks away
from our crime scene,
or, shall I say, 238 steps.
Don't tempt me with steps.
This is a defining moment for you.
You can either obey orders
for the rest of your life
and make no impact
on the world, or stand up!
And solve this case with me.
Is there a third option?
- Nervously tag along.
- Great.
I choose the nervously tag along option.
Okay, the reporters are all
set for your press conference.
It's your big moment, are you excited?
- No.
- Oh.
Are you worried
about your voice cracking?
Do you want me to help you
warm up your throat?
- What would that entail?
- I'll just show you.
Don't show me, tell me.
I blow hot air into my hands
and I stroke your neck.
That's not gonna happen,
and it's not why I'm stressed.
I think Holt got into my head.
We might have to delay
the press conference.
But this is the moment
we've been waiting for.
My dad's driving home early
from his brother's funeral
to watch it live.
Wait, he's doing what?
If you want me to put it
in a better context, I can't.
This was very important to him.
Holt is a great cop,
and I know the demotion's
driving him crazy,
but his gut is usually right.
I think we need to find
that hot dog cart guy.
Okay, fine.
But who do we know that could find us
a random New York hot dog guy?
[Def Leppard's "Pour Some Sugar on Me"]
♪ Hey
♪
♪ Hey!
So, you need a little help
from the Weiner Warriors.
Well, I hate that.
Just tell us what you know, please?
There's Lou's Dogs,
he serves 'em up real plump.
Big Mike's does two dogs per bun.
Hank's Franks...
great mustard selection.
Vicki's Vegan?
I'd rather eat [bleep].
Charlie does an Al dente dog,
it's got a really nice chew.
Johnny Arkansas serves it
Little Rock style,
although he can serve it
Razorback-style.
Okay, enough, enough!
We don't have time for this!
Just tell us who has a cart
at 6th and 11th.
Oh, there are no hot dog carts there.
What? Never?
- No way.
- Not a chance!
Zoning issue. Forget about it, Jake.
It's Hungertown.
Oh my God, Holt was right.
We have to call him.
Officer Holt?
Officer Holt, do you copy?
Okay, cop. Turn it off.
Nice try.
My partner doesn't follow orders.
Debbie, you're misreading the situation.
Oh. I'm so sorry.
We both... both follow orders.
So you were the shooter,
just like I said.
And the man in the hoodie
was just some random bystander
on whom you tried to pin it!
No, he was in on it too.
Oh.
Well, I'm still half right.
Sure. Is that important to you?
- Very.
- I'm gonna die.
I'm gonna die before I ever got to find
my twin sister's killer.
What?
That's the reason
I joined the force, remember?
To find the man
who murdered my twin sister.
That's my whole story!
Debbie, there's no way you told me that.
[groans loudly] Nothing's working!
Maybe you just need to laugh.
Here, look at this video of a
man being trampled by a moose.
[moose grunts, hooves clop]
[man screams]
Dear Lord, that's horrifying!
[chuckles] I know, it's hilarious.
What are you laughing at?
Is that a video of me?
Oh, no, is it that time
Terry fell off a Lime scooter?
Why would any of us have that footage?
Don't skirt the question!
I want to know what I'm
falling off of in that video.
Stop it, Terry, okay?
We haven't been talking about you!
[gasps] Oh. Kicking.
I think kicking's working.
Told you. Go with it.
Keep kicking that can.
[grunts]
[gasps]
It worked, I have to pee!
I finally have to pee!
Wait, this is about you having to pee?
- BOTH: Yes!
- Wow.
I guess I owe you guys an apology.
I may have been bringing
some things from home
into the workplace.
Yeah, that was clear
from the start, okay?
Now, move, I need to find a bathroom.
Stop, we have an emergency!
Everybody stop what you're about to do.
Yeah, but I gotta pee really bad.
Well, hold it, Amy.
Holt's not answering his radio.
I think he and Debbie
might be in trouble.
It's just us, man,
you don't have to pretend
to care about Debbie.
- Rosa!
- What?
We barely know her and she's annoying.
She's always trying to get
people to be friends with her
on that weird app for pedicures.
It's a pedometer app.
It's a pedometer app!
We can use the social features
to track her!
It's $80.
Uh, Boyle, you should download it,
you get better service here.
Smart!
And I'll upgrade to ad-free too.
- Smart.
- Okay, let's move!
Sweet! We're running, okay.
If I die, will you look after my cat?
I'm really more of a dog person.
I understand.
[door clanks]
- NYPD, nobody move!
- You're surrounded!
Don't do anything stupid.
Looks like we got ourselves a standoff.
Fine by us, we got
all the time in the world.
What? Uh-uh!
I gotta pee!
[growls]
- [blows land]
- [grunting]
Perp secured.
Great, okay, cool!
I gotta go! You guys are good, right?
Bye!
Thanks for saving us, Peralta.
Thank Debbie, we tracked you
using her pedometer app.
Oh, my goodness, I helped! [chuckles]
And I got four new Foot Friend requests!
What a day, guys! [laughs]
♪
Detective.
I believe I owe you an apology.
No, Officer, I owe you one.
No, I owe you.
Great, 'cause I hadn't thought of
what I was gonna apologize for yet.
I should not have disobeyed your order.
I was wrong.
Not about the case, of course,
my hunch was impeccable.
Interesting apology strategy,
a little heavy on the brags.
Point is, you were right.
I hijacked the case because
I need to feel respected.
[sighs] Listen,
it's weird that I'm your boss now,
and that's not going anywhere,
but no matter what uniform you wear,
I'm always gonna love you...
I mean, cherish...
I mean, respect.
- You said respect, right?
- Yes.
Yep.
And I feel the same about you.
So, do you have any orders for me, sir?
Well, I do actually
still need those cones picked up.
We're on it.
We got cone duty?
Yes!
Best birthday yet.
It's your birthday?
Hey, so...
today was pretty intense.
You mean catching the shooter?
I know, it's a great story.
I just hope Pitt
can get in good enough shape
to play me in the movie, you know?
Mm, yeah.
Um, also, something else happened.
I thought I might be pregnant.
- Really?
- Yeah.
I'm not, I got my period.
And I took a pregnancy test,
but it didn't work
because I drank 11 gallons of water.
Told you water was bad for you.
- That's not the takeaway.
- You're absolutely right.
How are you, how do you feel?
Are you okay?
I mean, I was really stressed.
This wasn't our plan,
and we agreed we'd wait a year
and there's so much to do first,
and it would've been crazy, right?
Yeah, it would've been.
Okay.
But...
also might've been...
kinda cool.
Honestly?
I was secretly bummed when
the test came back negative.
Should we just start trying?
Seriously?
Yeah, seriously.
Okay. Yeah.
[both chuckle]
[mellow music]
[chuckles]
Oh, wait! It's after 11.
- [gasps]
- My interview!
It's supposed to be on the news.
An incredible conclusion
to a terrifying day,
and we were able to get a comment
from the men who helped solve this case.
They call us the Weiner Warriors.
No!
Sync & corrections by emeline-whovian
www.addic7ed.com